Matt Browne

New York, NY | 719-651-8943 | mbrowne108@gmail.com LinkedIn URL | Github | Blog

FRONT-END/FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming specializing in React. Possess strong skills in collaboration and project organization. Also spent fifteen years earning a Doctorate in Music Composition, supplementing the above with unique creative thinking skills, soft skills, and proactivity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Active Record, Active Storage, Javascript, React, Redux, Postgres, SQL, CSS, Bootstrap

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Atlas of Curiosities - Github I Demo

Collection of user-added local historical sites incorporating Google Maps API.

- Incorporated Google Maps API to map each location and give real-time distance information to the user.
- Utilized Active Storage to include photos from each user's visit which is stored online via Cloudinary.
- Incorporated the Google Maps Geocoding API to convert addresses into coordinates and vice versa.
- Converted global state variables into a Redux framework to streamline code where state is used in several components.
- Styled the app using Bootstrap for a crisper, more modern look.

Kitchen Kingpin - Github | Demo

App to keep track of user made recipes, ingredients in the user's pantry, and a shopping list.

- Styled the app using Bootstrap, including color coding for ingredients to display low/empty inventory.
- Linked ingredients used in a recipe to the pantry so the user can see if they have everything to make it.
- Utilized a rails backend to store user-added recipes and ingredients.

Quotordle - Github | Demo

Wordle-like game where you are given a famous movie quote (+more hints) and must name the movie.

- Utilized a rails backend to store all movie information as well as user scores.
- Styled using Bootstrap to have a simple, Wordle-like appearance.
- Created a leaderboard showing all users to keep the game competitive.
- Utilized an array for several possible movie titles to keep the game flexible.

EXPERIENCE

Maestoso Music New York, NY

Freelance Composer and Arranger

09/2016 - Present

- Compose classical music for various ensembles ranging from opera to full orchestra.
- Arrange and compose scores for student and independent films.
- Handle a self-managed schedule of ongoing commission deadlines and performance dates.
- Collaborate closely with musicians, conductors, music directors, orchestras, and donors.

Village Community School

New York, NY 09/2018 - 03/2021

Music Composition Instructor

- Planned lectures, activities, and assignments for year-long middle school classes.
- Taught two classes a week including lectures, individual lessons, and hands-on workshops.
- Organized and curated live musician rehearsals, workshops, and concerts.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

New York, NY
07/2021 - 04/2022

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor Doctor of Musical Arts, Music Composition Ann Arbor, MI 09/2011 - 05/2016